<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Borealis Digital Studio blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[A collection of blogposts written by our employees]]></description><link>https://blog.borealisdigitalstudio.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 07:15:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Improving accessibility branding guidelines]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today the Borealis Branding guidelines are available in PDF format. It’s ideal to print out and to read it on physical paper but it’s…]]></description><link>https://blog.borealisdigitalstudio.com//digital-borealis-branding-guidelines/digital-borealis-branding-guidelines/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.borealisdigitalstudio.com//digital-borealis-branding-guidelines/digital-borealis-branding-guidelines/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 10:09:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today the Borealis Branding guidelines are available in PDF format. It’s ideal to print out and to read it on physical paper but it’s suboptimal in the reality of today where everyone is trying to read them on a computer screen. It’s hard to navigate the 128 pages if you are looking for one specific item like the Borealis blue hex colour value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second hassle is to find the latest version of the branding guidelines, new employees don’t know where they are and some employees don’t even know they exist. If however, you get the guidelines, you are never sure that you have the latest version. If there is a newer version available than what you currently have, you are probably too lazy to update it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another inconvenience is the lack of access to resources. When you read about the guidelines on how to use a logo, you don’t know where to download that specific logo. It happens quite often that someone downloads the Borealis logo from an unofficial source. This leads to the misuse of logos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarise the accessibility problems with the Borealis branding guidelines: Searchability, versioning and access to resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Proposed solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An online digital version of the branding guidelines in the form of a web application. Right now only a &lt;a href=&quot;https://sketch.cloud/s/v1D28/a/1ZZRwb/play&quot;&gt;static prototype&lt;/a&gt; has been developed to showcase the possible capabilities. &lt;a href=&quot;https://sketch.cloud/s/v1D28/a/1ZZRwb/play&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;please visit the link before reading further&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only parts of the guidelines have been prototyped to give an impression of which direction we want to take for the solution. When validated the rest of the guidelines can be prototyped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Navigation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prototype has a side navigation bar including the main items of the Borealis branding guidelines. It can easily be extended and the nature of the design keeps everything scannable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sketch.cloud/s/v1D28/a/bddyVZ/play&quot;&gt;Navigation preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Header&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The header contains a general search bar where anything within the guidelines can be found via a simple search query. Right next to the search bar there is a version selector. Here you can select the version of the design guide. Ideal for testing alpha/beta updates or to go back to previous versions to see the updates. Another nice to have is to see the changelogs for every version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sketch.cloud/s/v1D28/a/qkkyJe/play&quot;&gt;Header preview&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The search capabilities are not yet prototyped&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Specific developers features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the guidelines as a developer is a different experience since we can integrate the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/borealisgroup/borealis-js&quot;&gt;libraries&lt;/a&gt; that follow the guidelines. A toggle should enable developer features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So far this behaviour hasn’t been prototyped&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scannable and layered information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People on the web &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nngroup.com/articles/how-users-read-on-the-web/&quot;&gt;rarely read text word by word&lt;/a&gt;. They scan the page and pick out whatever they need. Following this reasoning we made some information layered. Most of the pages contain boxes with the following structure: Image, Title and expandable arrow icon. When the user clicks on the title or arrow it should expand and show more information like a description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sketch.cloud/s/v1D28/a/5eJmVp/play&quot;&gt;Expandable box preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So far the behaviour of opening and closing are not yet prototyped&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Logo page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this page, a user can configure the Borealis logo and download it as an SVG file. For developers, a code block from the logo library should appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you configure the logo in a way that is violating the guidelines, for example only selecting the Aurora icon with a solid background. Then a warning ⚠️ should appear explaining that this specific configuration is a violation of the guidelines and downloading the logo should become impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underneath the logo configuration, there is a section “don’ts” which explains the way the logo &lt;strong&gt;shouldn’t&lt;/strong&gt; be used. Since this information is so close to the place where users will get their logo, it will naturally lead to less misuse of the logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other information about the logo from the guidelines are listed underneath the “don’ts”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sketch.cloud/s/v1D28/a/1ZZRwb/play&quot;&gt;Logo page preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The warning hasn’t been prototyped yet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not all the don’ts and information boxes are listed to save time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Colours page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here users can find all the colours mentioned in the Borealis guidelines with a description for every category. Every colour has a name with a hex value that can easily be copied to the clipboard by clicking on it. Shades are also documented and the name of the shaded colour informs how much it deviates from the base colour. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;added colour values&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We added for every primary colour one darker shade level since we saw in some applications like a side navigation sub menu that darker shades are preferable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://osmium-storybook.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/images/myborealis-navbar.png&quot; alt=&quot;MyBorealis navigation bar&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also propose to add extra shades to the “additional indicator” colours for the UI elements displayed underneath which is used in some applications&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://osmium-storybook.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/images/alert-boxes.png&quot; alt=&quot;alert boxes showing shaded colours&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sketch.cloud/s/v1D28/a/3vzn7r/play&quot;&gt;Colours page preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Only the primary colours are shown as an example since it takes to much time to prototype all the colours, coding it would be way more time efficient&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Typography page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only typographic base values defined in the guidelines are font families. In our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/borealisgroup/borealis-js/blob/master/packages/theme/src/brands/borealis.json&quot;&gt;theming library&lt;/a&gt; we defined other values like font weight, line heights and font sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those typographic values are used for the configuration at the top of the page. An extra idea would be to add some preset values for paragraphs, titles (h1, h2, h3, …), links etc so that we also create consistency for those elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user can input their own text and copy the style via the “copy button” to the clipboard. When pasted in a program like Outlook it should keep the defined style if the correct fonts are set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real benefit here is for developers, for them we could create a CSS code block which is linked to the defined values. Completed integrated with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/borealisgroup/borealis-js/blob/master/packages/theme/src/brands/borealis.json&quot;&gt;theming library&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sketch.cloud/s/v1D28/a/1ZnbK4/play&quot;&gt;Typography page preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Icon page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current guidelines only describe how we should design custom icons and it has a couple of examples. But not enough to display a full icon package. So far within Borealis, we haven’t defined any icon package that should be used across digital projects. We propose to custom make or buy a guideline complaint icon package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To show an &lt;strong&gt;example&lt;/strong&gt; what it &lt;strong&gt;could&lt;/strong&gt; look like, we copied the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ant.design/components/icon/&quot;&gt;icon package from Ant Design&lt;/a&gt;. When clicking on an icon, it should download the SVG or if you are a developer it should also give you the option to copy the code from a library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ant.design/components/icon/&quot;&gt;Icon page preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Headline system page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A direct copy of the information described in the guidelines. Any extra information can be expanded from its respective box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sketch.cloud/s/v1D28/a/8m2lmY/play&quot;&gt;Headline system page preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Should branding guidelines be public or not?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many companies already put their branding guidelines publicly online. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbondesignsystem.com/&quot;&gt;IBM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lightningdesignsystem.com/&quot;&gt;Salesforce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.starbucks.com/static/reference/styleguide/&quot;&gt;Starbucks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issuu.com/logobr/docs/adobe_brand_guidelines&quot;&gt;Adobe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.audi.com/ci/en/renewed-brand.html&quot;&gt;Audi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/branding/&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.facebookbrand.com/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ggw-prototype.goalgorilla.com/&quot;&gt;Greenpeace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://walmartlabs.github.io/web-style-guide/&quot;&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://styleguides.io/examples.html&quot;&gt;…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making your branding guidelines public could bring the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It ensures that anyone who needs access to the guidelines can just access it with the click of a link. No need for login/registration pages or user management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes your branding guidelines crawlable for search engines like Google or Bing. When done right the following situation could happen: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jane Doe needs the Borealis logo but she doesn’t know that Borealis Branding guidelines exist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Jane doesn’t know where to find something she does what every smart person does, she goes to Google and searches: “Borealis Logo”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first link from the search result is a link from the official Borealis Branding Guideline logo page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jane clicks on that link because it’s exactly what she needs, she can configure/download the Borealis logo following the guidelines and immediately knows how she shouldn’t use it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jane now also knows that Borealis Branding guidelines exist and she bookmarks it for later use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making beautiful branding guidelines that are easy to use and accessible convinces naturally to anyone that we are taking a design at Borealis very seriously. Potential hires could be more eager to take a job at Borealis because of this attitude. You can even find &lt;a href=&quot;http://styleguides.io/examples.html&quot;&gt;online listings of professional branding guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reason to not do it is that you don’t want that the competition can look into our guidelines and copy them. If someone is copying our guidelines for their own use, it means that we are doing something right. So take it as a compliment. I couldn’t find any argument on Google supporting this statement, we just have to think twice about what we put public so that it doesn’t hurt our business.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Setting up a gatsby blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Let’s get startedBefore we start please make sure you have Git installed.Install nvmYou can skip this if you already have a working node…]]></description><link>https://blog.borealisdigitalstudio.com//setting-up-a-gatsby-blog/setting-up-a-gatsby-blog/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.borealisdigitalstudio.com//setting-up-a-gatsby-blog/setting-up-a-gatsby-blog/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Let’s get started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we start please make sure you have &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Install nvm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can skip this if you already have a working node installation, however I would still recommend using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a node version manager. It will allow you to install different versions of node on your machine and set the version per project you are working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On mac/linux run the following command in your terminal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-shell&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;curl&lt;/span&gt; -o- https://raw.githubusercontent.com/creationix/nvm/v0.33.0/install.sh &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;bash&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Windows have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coreybutler/nvm-windows&quot;&gt;nvm-windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pick a location for your blog, we’ll put it in &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;~/git/personal/blog&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up use nvm to install the latest, or a desired node version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-shell&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot;&gt;nvm &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; 12.2.0 &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;# This was the latest at the time of writing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can verify the node version for the current directory with &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;nvm current&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other useful nvm commands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-shell&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot;&gt;nvm &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;ls&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;# Versions installed on your system&lt;/span&gt;
nvm ls-remote &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;# All versions available for installation&lt;/span&gt;
nvm &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; VERSON_OF_NODE &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;# Install a specific version of node&lt;/span&gt;
nvm use VERSON_OF_NODE &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;# Set the node version for the folder you&apos;re in&lt;/span&gt;
nvm current &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;# Show the node version in use (node -v should return the same)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Setup Gatsby&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gatsby comes with a nice cli, install it using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;install &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;g gatsby&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;cli&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;run &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;gatsby -v&lt;/code&gt; to verify the installation at the time of writing: 2.5.12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Choose and install a starter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we’ll setup a new gatsby site through the cli, using this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/starters/gatsbyjs/gatsby-starter-blog/&quot;&gt;Gatsby starter&lt;/a&gt;, have a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt; before you use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like another one have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/starters/?s=blog&amp;#x26;v=2&quot;&gt;this list of starters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After choosing a starter run the following command, this will initialize the blog inside the directory you made earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;gatsby new . https://github.com/gatsbyjs/gatsby-starter-blog&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want the blog in a new folder replace the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; with the folder name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;verify the installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all went well your blog has been set up, however it is not running yet. Run &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;gatsby develop&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal. Now visit &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;http://localhost:8000&lt;/code&gt; and you should be able to see your bright and shiny new blog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course a blog needs content, in the current setup content is retrieved through markdown files in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;/content/blog&lt;/code&gt; folder so have a look at these if you want some examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown however does not have to be the only way of adding content, gatsby allows for you to integrate with multiple data sources. We’ll focus on markdown for now though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Adding a new blogpost&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add a new post simply add a new folder which contains you post eg: &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;/content/blog/dummy-post/dummy-post.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start of the post insert some metadata&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;yml&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-yml&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; You&apos;re post tile
&lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Date you are writing the post eg&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;2019-05-17T22:40:32.169Z&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;description&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; A small description which will be displayed in the post overview
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This data will be displayed somewhere on the blogpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below the data you can just start writing your blog as you would any mardown file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Altering data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since everyone has a slightly different use case, the current data provided might not be enough. Let’s change it a bit so it matches what we want to achieve. For our example we would like multiple people to write blogposts, it would be nice to have everyone write them in their own name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Graphql&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We retrieve data using &lt;a href=&quot;https://graphql.org/&quot;&gt;graphql&lt;/a&gt;, to test queries you can use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:8000/___graphql&quot;&gt;graphical interface&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example can be found on the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;/pages/index.js&lt;/code&gt; file At the bottom it has a query which should look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; pagequery &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; graphql&lt;span class=&quot;token template-string&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;`
  query {
    site {
      sitemetadata {
        title
      }
    }
    allmarkdownremark(sort: { fields: [frontmatter___date], order: desc }) {
      edges {
        node {
          excerpt
          fields {
            slug
          }
          frontmatter {
            date(formatstring: &quot;mmmm dd, yyyy&quot;)
            title
            description
          }
        }
      }
    }
  }
`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to add some info about the author to every blogpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Provide data in the blogpost&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This step is rather simple, we just add it at the top of our blogpost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eg:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;yml&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-yml&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; You&apos;re post tile
&lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Date you are writing the post eg&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;2019-05-17T22:40:32.169Z&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;description&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; A small description which will be displayed in the post overview
&lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;author&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Lewis Fidlers
&lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;authorSocial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;https://www.github.com/lewis-fidlers&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it, the data will now be available for us to query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Retrieve the data through your adapted query&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:8000/___graphql&quot;&gt;graphical interface&lt;/a&gt;, here we enter our updated query&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;  query &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    site &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      siteMetadata &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        title
      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;allMarkdownRemark&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token parameter&quot;&gt;sort&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; fields&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;frontmatter___date&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; order&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;DESC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      edges &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        node &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
          excerpt
          fields &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            slug
          &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
          frontmatter &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;formatString&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;MMMM DD, YYYY&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
            title
            description
            author
            authorAvatar
          &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This query requires a slug to find the actual post, so don’t forget to enter this in the query variables section.
For us it looks like this, of course you need to fill this in using your own &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;/folder/filename.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;{
  &amp;quot;slug&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;/dummy-post/dummy-post/&amp;quot;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all went well the result will now also return your author and the social link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Display it on the blog post&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our last step we’d like to update The data displayed int he blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open up the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;src/templates/blog-post.js&lt;/code&gt; file, this file is “conveniently” a template for every post we make from here on. At the bottom expand the query so it also queries our newly added data, as we did in the previous step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frontmatter part of the query should now look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;frontmatter &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;formatString&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;MMMM DD, YYYY&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  title
  description
  author
  authorSocial
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now move up in the file and change the Bio component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Bio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;author&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token script language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token script-punctuation punctuation&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;post&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;frontmatter&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;author&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;authorSocial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token script language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token script-punctuation punctuation&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;post&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;frontmatter&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;authorSocial&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we pass in the new data to the bio component&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last step we change the Bio component to display the newly provided info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open up &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;src/components/bio.js&lt;/code&gt; and change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;Written by &lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;strong&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;{author}&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;strong&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; who lives and works in San&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With something you want yourself, our example is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;Written by &lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token attr-value&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;{`${authorSocial}`}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;{author}&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for &lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;strong&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;{company}&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;strong&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;That should be about it&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should give you an idea of how to setup and change a blog using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/&quot;&gt;Gatsby&lt;/a&gt; and one of their starters. It is however still a pretty brief summary of what’s possible so please check out their docs and play with it.
Feel free to reach out if you have any questions, or if you find anything anything that’s incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>